<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-15T21:17:47+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Max Morehead</title><subtitle>This site contains information about my projects, qualifications, and thoughts on the world.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Spend Club Money</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2017/12/18/how-to-spend-club-money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Spend Club Money" /><published>2017-12-18T19:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T19:15:00+00:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2017/12/18/how-to-spend-club-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2017/12/18/how-to-spend-club-money.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a guide I wrote for clubs at my high school. This one is somewhat specific, but is is part
of a series of more general guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-a-budget&quot;&gt;Creating a budget&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, the club should create and approve a budget for the entire school
year. Details and help for this process can be found in “How to Create and Maintain a Club Budget”.
You should create a budget at the very beginning of the year and vote to approve it at your first
or second club meeting. Then, submit it to the school treasurer to be approved by ASB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;spending-money-that-has-been-budgeted&quot;&gt;Spending Money that Has Been Budgeted&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a budget approved, you need to go through a separate approval process to spend the
money you have in the account. For this process you’ll need one of the ASB expenditure approval
forms from the office. There are two ways you can buy items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Pay and be reimbursed: For small items, you can purchase the items with your own money or
your parents money and then be reimbursed for club funds. Make sure to keep all receipts from
the purchase, or else you won’t be reimbursed.

2. Purchase Order: For larger purchases, some websites and vendors offer a purchase order
website. Obtain a quote from the website for the items you wish to order and approve the
spending through the normal processes listed below. Then, talk to the school treasurer and
he/she will help you with the purchase order.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use either method, you must have the money in the club account and approve the
expenditure at one of your regular club meetings through the regular voting process. Make sure to
include the specific things you plan to buy and the maximum amount they will cost and to record
this in the club’s minutes. Then, fill out the ASB expenditure approval form with the information
from the meeting, have it signed by your club advisor, and hand it in to the school treasurer
(he/she can handle the other signatures). Make sure you include a copy of the club’s minutes. It
can also be helpful to include a quote or examples from online of the prices of the items you want
to buy to prove that the costs will be what you say they are. If the amount you need to spend
exceeds your budgeted amounts for the year, then you must vote on and submit a new, amended budget
along with the spending approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is extremely important that for both methods, you wait to actually purchase the items until
after the spending has been approved by both your club and the ASB. ASB approval can take up to a
week or more, so make sure you submit everything early. Also, if anything is shipped from online,
it must be shipped to the school. Once it has been shipped, two members from the club must sign a
list of the ordered items to ensure that every item has arrived. If you bought the item and need to
reimbursed, give the school treasurer the shipping list (if applicable) and the actual receipt
signed by two members of the club to verify the items have be received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any trouble figuring out how to spend your club’s money, talk to the school treasurer
and/or the ASB, and they can help you figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pre-approval&quot;&gt;Pre-approval&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an event or period for which unexpected expenditures might occur, you can seek
pre-approval for spending. At a regular meeting, vote on and approve a specific amount of money to
spend over a specific time period. You must have this money already in your club account. Then,
fill out and sign an ASB expenditure approval form, and submit it to the school treasurer to be
approved by ASB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the spending has been pre-approved, you can buy items within that pre-approval up to but not
exceeding the amount approved using either purchase orders or purchases with reimbursements. You
still need to give the treasurer the shipping list (if applicable) and actual receipt signed by two
members of the club to verify the items have be received in order to be reimbursed. Your internal
club procedures should insure that pre-approved money is being spent how the members want it to be
spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-approval is different and separate from setting a budget at the beginning of the year. For a
budget, you can plan to spend money you don’t have already, but for pre-approval, you are approving
for specific purposes the spending of money you already have. In order to spend money, you need
both a budget and spending approval.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Morehead</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">This is a guide I wrote for clubs at my high school. This one is somewhat specific, but is is part of a series of more general guides.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2017/12/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-12-14T02:38:01+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-14T02:38:01+00:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2017/12/14/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2017/12/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>